This summer, Prince Akeem discovers America.
Coming to America is a comedy, romance film directed by John Landis.
An African prince decides it’s time for him to find a princess...
and his mission leads him and his most loyal friend to Queens, New York.
In disguise as an impoverished immigrant, the pampered prince quickly finds himself
a new job, new friends, new digs, new enemies and lots of trouble.
Prince Akeem / Clarence / Randy Watson / Saul, played by Eddie Murphy.
Semmi / Extremely Ugly Girl / Morris / Reverend Brown, played by Arsenio Hall.
Lisa McDowell, played by Shari Headley.
Cleo McDowell, played by John Amos.
King Jaffe Joffer, played by James Earl Jones.
Queen Aoleon, played by Madge Sinclair.
Coming to America is a 1988 American romantic comedy film directed by John Landis, based on a
story originally created by Eddie Murphy, written by David Sheffield and Barry W.
Blaustein, and starring Murphy (in various roles), Arsenio Hall (also in various
roles), James Earl Jones, John Amos, Madge Sinclair, and Shari Headley.
It tells the story of Akeem Joffer, the crown prince of the fictional African nation of Zamunda who travels to the United States in the hopes
of finding a woman he can marry and will love him for who he is, not for his status or for having been trained to please him.
The film was released in the United States on June 29, 1988, and
received generally positive reviews from critics.
It was also a box-office success, grossing an estimated
$288.8–$350 million on a $36 million budget.
In 1989, a pilot for a planned spin-off television series was
made, although this was never picked up for a series.
A sequel to the film—Coming 2 America—was released on March 4, 2021.
The film explores themes of new york city, fast food
restaurant, prince, fake identity, heir to the throne.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.